# JEFFERSON ARBOLEDA

Nice, Côte d'Azur, France \* +33 6 49 32 54 50 \* me@jarboleda.me \* https://www.jarboleda.me/ LinkedIn \* GitHub

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Agile Business Analyst with three years' experience in customer facing activities in a B2B context, providing technical knowledge and data insights on our products. Previously, I worked as a Software Engineer for two years in ecommerce projects, establishing an agile methodology for my department.

# CORE COMPETENCIES

- Requirements Gathering and Analysis
- Business Process Modeling (BPM)

- Data Visualization
- Detail Oriented

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

AMADEUS (MOBILITY AND INSURANCE, ALTEN), FRANCE. Oct 2017 – Present

- Collaborate with stakeholders to gather business requirements and translate them into working IT solutions, achieving a 100% volume increase in a fast-paced B2B migration context (Expedia.com, Kayak.com).
- Travel with business team for pre-sales purposes (Kayak.com, US), creating dashboards with visualizations about the product and deep diving on its capabilities.
- Gather data insights to drive prioritization of items in the team's backlog, using internal APIs and Python.
- Was the facilitator of the maintenance team for eight months, achieving over the target on opened records by the end of year, and taking ownership of maintenance tasks for two different products.

Competencies: Python/SQL, Excel, Splunk, Jira, Scrum, Kanban, Specifications writing, Functional testing, API, C++.

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

TCSET (E-COMMERCE SOLUTIONS), SPAIN. Jun 2015 - Sep 2016

- Managed the full cycle of six projects, from gathering requirements to maintenance and customer training.
- Optimized SQL data handling to improve catalog updates over +100k products for our own e-commerce portal.
- Reduced incoming weekly tickets by 40% by creating customer ready documentation about our products.
- Reduced downtime to zero by re-engineering and simplifying company's processes, such as deployments to production or reducing 3<sup>rd</sup> party dependencies.
- Mentored an intern in day-to-day operations and best practices.

Competencies: SQL, PHP, JavaScript, CSS, Magento, SDLC, Product Ownership.

#### **INTERNSHIP**

TCSET, Spain. Feb 2015 – May 2015

Helped in managing domains owned by the company (100+) and migrations between services providers.

**Competencies:** IT Services migrations (DNS).

## **EDUCATION**

#### MASTER'S IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING (DATA SCIENCE)

University of Castilla-La Mancha, 2017

#### **DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING**

University of Castilla-La Mancha, 2011 – 2015

#### LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native Language)
- French (Conversant B2)

English (C1 – Cambridge CAE)